

CONTACT

- +1 480-919-5726
- ✓ albelop1m@gmail.com
- Arizona, USA (Temp) Mexico City (Permanent)

EDUCATION

UTEL UNIVERSITY

 B.S. Computer Systems Engineering

KODEMIA

• Full Stack Web Development

SKILLS

- Javascript
- Front-end Development:
 HTML, CSS, React, Angular,
 Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap
- AWS & Google Cloud
- Back-end Development:
 Node.js, MongoDB, Express...
- Project Management: SCRUM,
 PMI, ITIL, ISO 20000-1
- Version Control: Git & GitHub
- Leadership
- Critical Thinking

LANGUAGES

- English (Intermediate)
- Spanish (Native)

RICARDO LÓPEZ

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

PROFILE

Full Stack Developer with over three years of experience in enterprise web applications and more than ten years in IT Project Management. Specialized in technologies like React, Angular, HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript. Extensive experience in creating SPAs, optimizing resources, and deploying in containers such as AKS and Docker. Additionally, I have strong project leadership skills, ensuring scalable and efficient solutions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SICA Talento

Full Stack Developer

MARCH 2021 - PRESENT

I led the development of a rebranded website for Sica Talento, enhancing user experience, and built a custom CRM system integrated with a job posting and application platform, similar to ZipRecruiter and Indeed. This streamlined recruitment processes and improved efficiency. I also developed enterprise Single Page Applications using Angular6+, optimized performance with responsive design and Lazy-loading, and implemented CI/CD pipelines using Docker and GitHub. Additionally, I coordinated Agile teams to consistently deliver projects on time and within scope.

SONDA

May 2017 - March 2021

System Analyst

I led the implementation of the CA IT Client Manager platform to connect and control all desktop and laptop devices at Palacio de Hierro, one of the largest companies in Mexico, allowing centralized access and control of the equipment. I coordinated distributed teams using Agile methodologies (Scrum), optimizing the infrastructure for scalability and maintenance, and delivered the project on time.

Datavision Digital

May 2014 - May 2017

IT Project Manager

Led the FIRA project, managing a \$500,000 budget and delivering it on time. Implemented ISO 20000-1 certification, improving IT service management processes and reducing response times by 20%. Additionally, I coordinated multidisciplinary teams to implement technological solutions that optimized delivery times and service quality.

REFERENCE

Guillermo Villanueva

Administrative Services Manager / Ben & Frank

Phone: +52 5561160820

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/guillermo-

villanueva-rodriguez/

Ramon O. Muñoz

IAM DB Manager / Santander

Phone: +52 5518249353

Email: roctaviomc@yahoo.com